Guide to the William Sloane Coffin, Jr. Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1931-2006; Accession 2010-M-066
  - Writings
    - Willamette University commencement speech, 2001 May 13 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - "Women and Men: Sharing Holy Ground", 1999 January 4-8 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - "Workers in the Vineyard", 1994 September 4 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "The Work of Christmas", 1994 January 2 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "Works of Darkness", Undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Writings fragments, Undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - "Yale Class of 1968", 2003 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - "Yale College in the '60s, the Years of Bush, Cheney, and Lieberman", Undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Yale Russian Chorus 50th anniversary, Undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Yale University Commencement, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - "You Corrupted Your Wisdom for the Sake of Your Splendor," Connecticut Christian Council of Churches, 2003 May 1 (Box 15, Folder 27-28)
    - Younger, George, eulogy, 2001 December 9 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Personal/biographical data
    - Awards and honors, 1948-2005 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Beecher lectures, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Biographical data from various authors, 1982-2005 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Book covers, Undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Book reviews, 1982-2005 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Buckley School report cards, 1931-1934 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - City of Wilmington, NC proclamation, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Event flyers, 1979-2003 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Event programs, 1967-2000 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Family genealogy, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Get well card, Undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Henry Sloane Coffin, 1945-1980 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Hotel reservation receipt, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Letters to mother, Undated (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - Memorandum of agreement for authorship, 1998 September 28 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Memorial service for William Sloane Coffin, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Military entry permit, Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Once to Every Man -- reviews, 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - News clippings, 1974-2006 (Box 17, Folder 7-8)
    - Pacific School of Religion commencement, 1993 May 13 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Phone numbers, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Photographs
      - William Sloane Coffin, Undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - William Sloane Coffin and others, Undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Family, Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Plane ticket, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - "Remembering William Sloane Coffin, Jr.", 2006 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Schedules, 1990-2002 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Sympathy cards for mother's death, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - "The Things That Make for Peace," American Baptist Peace Conference, 1992 November 17-19 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - "The Courage to Love", 1982 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Westminster John Knox Press publishing agreement, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Yale, 1942-1993 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Additional Material, 2001-2006; Accession 2014-M-006; 0.27; (12 boxes)
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Transferred from Yale Divinity Library, 2013.
  - "God Bless America" sermon for Kentucky Council of Churches, 2001 October; 1 (Box 1)
  - "Who Tells You Who You Are" sermon at N.U., 2001 October; 1 (Box 1)
  - William Sloane Coffin: A Lover's Quarrel with America, on Reel Independent: Vermont's Film Showcase [commercially produced], 2004 January 17; 1 (Box 2)
    Kenneth Peck interviews producer Ann Macksoud, bookending an airing of her documentary.
    Audio and video are slightly out of syncronization on the original videocassette.
  - "On Courage" [commercially produced], 2004; 1 (Box 3)
    General
    Excerpt from William Sloane Coffin: An American Prophet, produced by Old Dog Documentaries, Inc., copyright 2004 by Westminster John Knox Press.
  - "If Faith Puts Us on the Road, Hope Keeps Us There" [commercially produced], 2004; 1 (Box 4)
  - "A Politically Engaged Spirituality," speech at The Public Witness and Ministry of William Sloane Coffin, Jr. event, 2005 April 28; 1 (Box 5)
  - William Sloane Coffin, Jr. dinner, 2005 April 28; 2 (Box 6–7)
  - Coffin Memories, Circa 2006; 1 (Box 8)
    Interviews and video messages to Coffin, probably in Yale Commons.
  - William Sloane Coffin funeral, 2006 April 20; 2 (Box 9–10)
  - Splendor and Wisdom: The Reverend William Sloane Coffin, Jr. and the Yale Class of 1968 [commercially produced], 2006 June; 1 (Box 11)
    Advance screener copy of work-in-progress documentary by Lloyd Kaufman, Troma Entertainment Inc.
  - List of people making personal tributes to Bill Coffin on April 28, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 1)